Justin M. Lugo

275 Medford St. #111 Charlestown, Massachusetts 02129

Phone: (252) 503-1948 | Email: jlug331221@gmail.com Website: https://jlug331221.github.io/personal-website/ LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/justin-lugo/

Career Summary

Computer scientist/software engineer and Marine Corps veteran with 2+ years of professional software development experience. Huge passion for developing amazing applications. Always eager and open to new challenges that will help me grow as a developer. Previous positions include working within Formula 1 and the United States Air Force. Education includes a Bachelor's degree and Master's degree in Computer Science.

Education and Training

August 2016 - May 2018
 Texas Tech University

M.Sc. in Computer Science, GPA: 4.0 on a 4.0 Scale

SMART Scholarship Recipient

August 2013 - May 2016
 East Carolina University

B.Sc. in Computer Science, GPA: 3.81 on a 4.0 Scale

Relevant Courses:

Advanced Data Structures
Analysis of Algorithms
Programming Languages
Advanced Operating Systems
Software Project Management
Logic for Computer Scientists

Database Management Computer Architecture Software Engineering

A.I. - Intelligent Agents, Knowledge Representation and Reasoning

Theory and Practice of Logic Programming

June 2009 - June 2013

United States Marine Corps

Military Occupational Specialty: 0651 - Data Cyber Network Specialist Specialized Training: Cisco Networking, VMWare, NetApp Filers, Microsoft Server, Microsoft Windows and multiple Linux environments

Experience and Technical Skills

Languages	Java, C/C++, PHP, Python, BASH scripting, C#, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript
	(VueJS and React), Prolog, and Answer Set Programming (Clingo and
	SPARC)
Source Control	Git and DevOps
Web Frameworks	Laravel and ASP.NET
Operating Systems	Linux, Windows, Mac
Database Systems	MySQL and NoSQL
CFD	ParaView post processing automation with Python. STAR-CCM+
	automation with Java.

Professional Accomplishments

Haas F1 Team | June 2019 to July 2020 | Software Engineer

- Maintain the Python codebase for ParaView post-processing of the CFD simulation results
- Setup and configure version control (Git) with Azure DevOps for all software development source code
- Develop and maintain a timekeeping application with Laravel/VueJS
- Performed MSSQL database setup and configuration.
- Assist with the setup and current maintenance of a Laravel CFD web application.

Tinker Air Force Base | June 2018 to June 2019 | Computer Scientist

- Maintained software for the suite of applications within the E3 AWACS aircraft
- Worked within a Scrum team and in an Agile development setting
- Responsibilities were to resolve software faults and improve legacy code
- Relevant languages: C++, Java, and shell scripting

Texas Tech University, College of Media and Communications | September 2016 to July 2017 | Web Developer

- Managed the College of Media and Communications website
- Made updates to the site and creation of new site content

United States Marine Corps | March 2010 to May 2013 | Data Cyber Network Specialist

- Responsible for 24/7 IT help desk support
- Installation and configuration of Cisco routers and switches

Employment History

• July 2020 – Present

Software Engineer - MCR LLC, Boston, MA

• June 2019 - July 2020

Software Engineer - Haas F1 Team, Kannapolis, NC

June 2018 - June 2019

Computer Scientist - Tinker Air Force Base, Oklahoma City, OK

• July 2017 - May 2018

Full Time Graduate Student with the SMART Scholarship - Texas Tech University

• September 2016 - July 2017

Web Developer - Texas Tech University, College of Media and Communications Lubbock, TX

• July 2016 - August 2016

Teaching Assistant - Austin Coding Academy

San Antonio, TX

• June 2016 - August 2016

Lead Instructor | Teaching Assistant - Youth Code Jam San Antonio

San Antonio, TX

• September 2015 - April 2016

Biology Tutor | IT Lab Administrator - East Carolina University, Athletic Student Development Greenville, NC

• October 2013 - August 2015

Student Laboratory IT Technician - East Carolina University, IT Computing Services Greenville, NC

• June 2009 - June 2013

Data Cyber Network Specialist - U.S Marine Corps

Jacksonville, NC